mecu.org 2014-11-23

# Privacy Policy

Home > Privacy Policy

##  Total Protection Guarantee 

We safeguard your funds, your privacy and your transactions.

FACTS | WHAT DOES MECU DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?  
---|---  
Why? | Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
---|---  
What? | The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the accounts or services you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Name, address, Social Security Number, and income 
  * Account balances and payment history 
  * Credit history and credit scores

When you are _no longer_ a member of MECU, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.  
  
---|---  
How? | All financial companies need to share members' personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their members' personal information; the reasons MECU chooses to share, and whether you can limit this sharing.  
---|---  
Reasons we can share your personal information| Does MECU share?| Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes —**  
such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus | Yes | No  
**For our marketing purposes —**  
to offer our products and services to you | Yes | No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies —** | Yes | No  
**For our affiliates' everyday business purposes —**  
information about your transactions and experiences | No | We do not share  
**For our affiliates' everyday business purposes —**  
information about your creditworthiness | No | We do not share  
**For our affiliates to market to you** | No | We do not share  
**For non-affiliates to market to you** | No | We do not share  
Questions? | 

  * Call 847.576.5199 or toll-free at 877.270.6392 (outside Illinois) or 
  * Visit us online at mecu.org

---|---  
Who we are  
---  
**Who is providing this notice?** | MECU.  
What we do  
---  
**How does MECU protect my personal information?** | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards, secured files and buildings, procedural safeguards and safe record storage. We will continue to review and modify our security controls in the future to deal with changes in products, services and technology.  
  
**How does MECU collect my personal information?** | We collect your personal information, for example, when you **** — ****

  * open an account 
  * apply for a loan 
  * use your credit or debit card 
  * pay your bills 
  * make deposits to or withdrawals from your accounts

We also collect your personal information from others, including credit bureaus or other companies.  
  
**Why can't I limit all sharing?** | Federal law only gives you the right to limit: 

  * sharing for affiliates' everyday business purposes — information about your creditworthiness 
  * affiliates from using your information to market to you 
  * sharing for non-affiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.  
  
Definitions  
---  
**Affiliates** | Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * MECU has no affiliates.

**Non-affiliates** | Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * MECU does not share with non-affiliates so they can market to you.

**Joint marketing** | A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you. 

  * Investment companies 
  * Insurance companies 
  * Other financial service providers

© 2012 Farleigh Wada Witt. All rights reserved. |  May 2012  
---|---  

##  Be advised 

You have chosen to follow a link to a website that resides outside of mecu.org. 

MECU, its affiliates, parents, directors, employees, agents, sponsors and partners are not responsible for the content that you may experience as a result of visiting this website.
